Guide to the ILGWU. Sol Chaikin papers,
ILGWU. Sol Chaikin papers,
- Series III. Regional Departments, 1938-1986
  - New England Region, 1975-1986 (Box 5, Folder 17-31)
    With Edward Milano, Director; Ronald Alman, Director re hiring and transferring of staff; NLRB election of Malden Mills, Inc.; need for an industrial engineer for New England shops; complaints and grievances of members; efforts to organize the mechanics of Hudson Mills by ILG and Teamsters; negotiations with David H. Smith, Inc.; strike of Homemakers Services in Fall River; racial discrimination suits by Harrison Beach Inc. (Boston); complaints about Business Agent; negotiations with Collegetown-Panther Shipper; alleged misconduct in election of officers of Local 361, New Bedford; Woodlawn/Lincoln in Fall River as "non-organizable"; draft of plan of reorganization of Malden Mills, Inc. and financial forecast; plant closings; unfair labor practice charges against Workroom for Designers, Inc. and subsequent strike.
  - New England region [folder 1 of 5], 1975-1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Clippings and booklet re Local 178 (Fall River) 50th anniversary; dismissal of discrimination charge by Massachusetts Commission Against Discrimination; articles re Fall River locals not providing Portuguese translator at union meetings; 5 p. Professional and Commercial Employees (PACE) form letter and question and answer sheets re organizing of employees' associations (affiliated with ILGWU); correspondence re Zayre negotiations; and other related routine.
  - New England region [folder 2 of 5], 1975-1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Clippings and booklet re Local 178 (Fall River) 50th anniversary; dismissal of discrimination charge by Massachusetts Commission Against Discrimination; articles re Fall River locals not providing Portugese translator at union meetings; 5 p. Professional and Commercial Employees (PACE) form letter and question and answer sheets re organizing of employees' associations (affiliated with ILGWU); correspondence re Zayre negotiations; and other related routine.
  - New England region [folder 3 of 5], 1975-1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - New England region [folder 4 of 5], 1975-1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - New England region [folder 5 of 5], 1975-1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - New Jersey Region, 1979-1986 (Box 6, Folder 6-19)
    With Edward Kramer, General Manager and Emanuel Leventhal, Assistant; Sol Goldberg, Director re staff problems, Local 133, Union City, NJ; members complaints and grievances; shop closings; concerns of retirees; unemployment compensation matters; liquidated damages paid by Evan-Picone, Inc. for non-union production; staff problems, Local 134, Paterson; severance pay for workers of Glen Sportswear; raid by IRS and immigration agents of Fashion Associates (Passaic, NJ); case of no-raiding between ILG Local 166 and Teamsters; inner local politics of Local 134, N & R Fashions; and related routine.
  - Northeast Department, 1938-1945 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Includes meeting announcements (Local 226, Springfield, Massachusetts and others); correspondence of Max Chansky, General Organizer of Western Massachusetts and David Gingold, Director, Cotton Garment and Miscellaneous Trades Department; and miscellaneous.
  - Northeast Department, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Gingold correspondence with Sol Chaikin, District Manager, Local 226 re expiration of agreements, staff meetings, organizing, expenses and related routine; also includes reports, form letters, monthly expense statements.
  - Northeast Department, 1948-1951 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    With Chaikin re expenses; strike at Active Sportswear and Diane Marion of Worcester, Mass.; 33 p. "Minutes, Northeast Dept. Conference, May 25-27, 1951;" assignment of organizers; 2 p. letter (8/13/51) from Chaikin to Gingold re state of the union analysis and organizing activities and related routine.
  - Northeast Department, 1952-1957 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Chaikin and Ralph A. Roberts, District Manager, Western Mass. District with Gingold re financial data, non-union jobbers, activities in Western Mass. District; industrial homework; organizing and related routine.
  - Northeast Department, 1958-1965 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    re renewal of agreements, organizing, and related routine.
  - Northeast Department [folder 1 of 2], 1958-1968 (Box 6, Folder 24a)
    Chaikin, Associate Director, re organizing activities, contract negotiations; political campaign contributions; strike at Malone Knitting Mills (Springfield); and other department activities.
  - Northeast Department [folder 2 of 2], 1958-1968 (Box 6, Folder 24b)
  - Northeast Department, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    8 p. report for the GEB by Chaikin and Gingold; financial; price settlements in the dress industry; and related routine.
  - Northeast Department, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    re Teamsters organizing office workers and sewing machine mechanics and related routine.
  - Northeast Department [folder 1 of 2], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    Between Chaikin, Secretary-Treasurer, ILGWU, and David Gingold, Director and others re severance pay due to shutdown of Barbizon Corp. (PA); Department of Labor representatives investigating procedure of election of District Council delegates (PA); 40th anniversary of Local 178, Fall River, Massachusetts; employee's grievances; Bali Inc. (Johnstown, PA) closing and incorporating with Bali in Puerto Rico and related routine.
  - Northeast Department [folder 2 of 2], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Northeast Department [folder 1 of 3], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Request by New England Apparel Manufacturers Association and others to defer wage increases due to condition of the industry; health care for members; strike of employees at T & T Fashions and Stephanie Fashions (PA); congratulation letters on Chaikin's election to the presidency; employee complaints and grievances and other related routine.
  - Northeast Department [folder 2 of 3], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    Request by New England Apparel Mftrs. Association and others to defer wage increases due to condition of the industry; health care for members; strike of employees at T & T Fashions and Stephanie Fashions (PA); congratulation letters on Chaikin's election to the presidency; employee complaints and grievances and other related routine.
  - Northeast Department [folder 3 of 3], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Northeast Department [folder 1 of 2], 1976 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    With Atlantic Apparel Contractors Association re survival of the industry; organizing drive in Johnstown, PA; 10 p. chronology and correspondence re work stoppage at Charland Sportswear (PA), and other related routine matters.
  - Northeast Department [folder 2 of 2], 1976 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Northeast Department, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    re member grievances; includes organizing report from Bernard Lurye, District Manager and related routine.
  - Northeast Department, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    Includes financial data; layoffs at Dalton Corp. (Ohio) and related routine.
  - Northeast Department, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    Member complaints; re ILG legal representation in Pennsylvania.
  - Northeast Department [folder 1 of 3], 1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    re decline of Ship N Shore sales; grievances of employees; wage increases at Sunset Mftg. Co. and routine.
  - Northeast Department [folder 2 of 3], 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Northeast Department [folder 3 of 3], 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Northeast Department [folder 1 of 3], 1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Staff engineer report of Masontown Mfg. Co. to improve productivity and earning potential; complaints and grievances of employees and other related routine.
  - Northeast Department [folder 2 of 3], 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Northeast Department [folder 3 of 3], 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Northeast Department [folder 1 of 4], 1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    re sweatshop conditions at Fernbrook, Inc. (PA); staff engineer report on Temple Industries (Reading, PA) investigating piece rate system; employee grievances.
  - Northeast Department [folder 2 of 4], 1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Northeast Department [folder 3 of 4], 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Northeast Department [folder 4 of 4], 1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Northeast Department, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 11-19)
    Employee complaints and grievances re benefits eligibility; plant shut down (Sharwell Mftg., Williamsport, PA); and other related routine.
  - Northeast Department [folder 1 of 3], 1984 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Employee complaints and grievances.
  - Northeast Department [folder 2 of 3], 1984 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Northeast Department [folder 3 of 3], 1984 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Northeast Department [folder 1 of 3], 1985 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Same as above; plant closings; includes a 6 p. letter from Chaikin, 10/10/85 in answer to many complaints from a member about the operation of the union (re negotiations, imports, benefits, dues, etc.).
  - Northeast Department [folder 2 of 3], 1985 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Northeast Department [folder 3 of 3], 1985 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Northeast Department [folder 1 of 2], 1986 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    re lay-offs, shut downs; complaints and grievances, and related routine.
  - Northeast Department [folder 2 of 2], 1986 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Northeast Department (Box 7, Folder 28)
    Undated. Related routine.
  - Ohio-Kentucky, 1973-1978 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    Employee grievances and complaints; and related routine.
  - Puerto Rico, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    re report on progress of negotiations of Puerto Rican Corset and Brassiere Association and Harwood Mftg. Corp.; flood relief; Minutes of Annual Meeting of Board of Trustees of Local 601 Puerto Rico Health and Welfare Fund (1975); shop closings; cooperative AFL-CIO organizing drive in Puerto Rico and related routine.
  - Puerto Rico, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    re negotiations; organizing; re-location of plants, and related routine.
  - Puerto Rico, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    re medical services for members; grievances of members and other related routine.
  - Puerto Rico, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    re negotiations and agreement with Bali Co., Inc. and other related routine.
  - Puerto Rico, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    re plant closings; housing project and related routine.
  - Puerto Rico, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    re contract violations by Vivo Inc.; re 25th anniversary of ILGWU in Puerto Rico and related routine.
  - Puerto Rico, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    3 p. "Interim Report" on Puerto Rico union activities by Clifford Depin, Vice-President and Regional Director and related routine.
  - Puerto Rico, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Strike against Applique Inc.; 5 p. report on activities in Puerto Rico; reduction of organizing staff; and related routine.
  - Puerto Rico, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    re contract violations with Splendorform, Inc. and Bestform Foundations; employees grievances.
  - Puerto Rico, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    30 p. "Amended By-Laws, Rules and Regulations of the Puerto Rican ILGWU Health and Welfare Fund"; and related routine.
  - Southeast Region [folder 1 of 2], 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    With Nicholas S. Bonanno, Director, re organizing; off-shore operations of Jonathan Logan, Bobbie Brooks and others; shop closings; employees grievances.
  - Southeast Region [folder 2 of 2], 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Southeast Region [folder 1 of 2], 1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Organizing Ship N Shore plants and others; employees grievances; election petitions; company propaganda, and related routine.
  - Southeast Region [folder 2 of 2], 1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Southeast Region [folder 1 of 2], 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Vanity Fair propaganda; use of non-union contractors by Puritan Co,; major organizing drive proposed for Sumter, South Carolina. Complaints and grievances; and related routine.
  - Southeast Region [folder 2 of 2], 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Southeast Region [folder 1 of 2], 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Organizing; negotiations with Baxley Industries; member's complaints; and related routine.
  - Southeast Region [folder 2 of 2], 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Southeast Region [folder 1 of 3], 1981 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Employee grievances and complaints; Savannah Wholesale strike; reduction of ILG staff due to economics; and related routine.
  - Southeast Region [folder 2 of 3], 1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Southeast Region [folder 3 of 3], 1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Southeast Region [folder 1 of 3], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Shop closings; 6 p. "A Proposal for the Establishment of A New Political Coalition" presented to labor leadership of Alabama; complaints and grievances; and related routine.
  - Southeast Region [folder 2 of 3], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Southeast Region [folder 3 of 3], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Southeast Region [folder 1 of 2], 1983 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Member complaints; negotiations between ILG and Spring City Knitting Co. (Cartersville, GA); arbitration case between Local 516 and Coastal Industries, Inc. re disciplinary suspension of employee; and related routine.
  - Southeast Region [folder 2 of 2], 1983 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Southeast Region [folder 1 of 2], 1984 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Member grievances; agreements with Stephanie Fashions and Coosa River Garment Co. (Alabama); organizing Kellwood plant (Mississippi); and related routine.
  - Southeast Region [folder 2 of 2], 1984 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Southeast Region [folder 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Grievances and related routine.
  - Southeast Region [folder 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Southeast Region [folder 1 of 2], 1986 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    Also undated. Shop closings; grievances and related routine.
  - Southeast Region [folder 2 of 2], 1986 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Upper South Department, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    With Sol Hoffman, Director re furnishings for offices; organizing in New Martinsville, West Virginia and related routine.
  - Upper South Department, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    Grievances; Teamsters raiding in Baltimore, MD; and related routine.
  - Upper South Department, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Upper South Department, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    With Peter Nadash, Director re organizing; employee grievances; company propaganda; and related routine.
  - Upper South Department [folder 1 of 2], 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    re employee grievances and complaints; and related routine.
  - Upper South Department [folder 2 of 2], 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Upper South Department [folder 1 of 2], 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Grievances; plant closings; negotiations and contract for Brownsville Mfg. Co. (Kentucky); and related routine.
  - Upper South Department [folder 2 of 2], 1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Upper South Department [folder 1 of 3], 1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Grievances and complaints; negotiations; arbitration with West Virginia Garment Co. re seniority; shop closings; negotiations between Local 402 and Lorraine Mftg. Co.; and related routine.
  - Upper South Department [folder 2 of 3], 1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Upper South Department [folder 3 of 3], 1983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Upper South Department, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Upper South Department [folder 1 of 2], 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Grievances; shop closings and related routine.
  - Upper South Department [folder 2 of 2], 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Western States, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    With Cornelius Wall, Director re contracts and negotiations; SK & K strike in San Pedro, CA; and grievances.
  - Western States [folder 1 of 2], 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Grievances; indictments of L.A. Trustee of ILG Health and Welfare Funds on charges of racketeering; need for Chinese officers in Local 101, San Francisco; and related routine.
  - Western States [folder 2 of 2], 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Western States, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Negotiations; grievances; additional correspondence re Local 101 difficulties; staffing problems with Cornelius Wall and related routine.
  - Western States, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Western States, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Grievances; negotiations and related routine.
  - Western States [folder 1 of 3], 1983 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Complaints and grievances; correspondence re earthquake hazard reduction in ILG Building and Los Angeles Redevelopment Project offer to buy building; and related routine.
  - Western States [folder 2 of 3], 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Western States [folder 3 of 3], 1983 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Western States, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Additional information on ILG buildings; and related routine.
  - Western States, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    Member complaints and grievances; import problem; effort of AFSCME to organize office and janitorial employees of Southwest District Council; and related routine.
- Series IV. Joint Boards, 1956-1984
  - Dallas Joint Board, 1956-1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    re organizing efforts in San Antonio (1956);and related routine.
  - Los Angeles Joint Board, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 1a)
    re merger of Cloak, Dress and Sportswear Joint Boards; and related routine.
  - New York Cloak Board, 1974-1978 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    With Howard Molisani, General Manager and others re imports; work being sent south; wages; re survey of firms to determine worker-employer attitudes; dues; and related routine.
  - New York Dress Joint Board, 1974-1978 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    With Murray Gross, General Manager re merger of Dress and Cloak Joint Boards; Dress Industry Holiday Fund; and related routine.
  - New York Joint Board [folder 1 of 3], 1978-1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    With Samuel Nemaizer, General Manager re wage increase (cost of living); ILGWU Bail Bond Program; non union work; imports; Tahari, Ltd. contracting work; strike of Parallel Lines, Inc.; financial information; re-organization of Joint Board; and related routine.
  - New York Joint Board [folder 2 of 3], 1978-1984 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - New York Joint Board [folder 3 of 3], 1978-1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - New York Sportswear Joint Board, 1980-1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Use of non-union contractors; and related routine.
  - Philadelphia Joint Board, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    With Irwin Solomon, Manager, re related routine matters.
  - San Francisco Joint Board, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    re organizational structure and related routine.
  - South Jersey Joint Board, 1981-1984 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Series V. Councils (Joint and District), 1950-1986
  - Joint Councils. Charters and By-Laws, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    re formation of Philadelphia Area Council and the Dress Makers' Joint Council.
  - District Council. Charter Application. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Undated. Forms.
  - Miami Joint Council, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    re imports; Cuban refugees.
  - New York State District, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    With Sol Goldberg, Director, re complaints and related routine.
  - New York State District, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Complaints; strike of Cotrell and Leonard re unfair labor practice and related routine.
  - New York State District, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Complaints; report re non-union contractors in N.Y. District and related routine.
  - New York State District [folder 1 of 2], 1982 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    With Salvatore Giardina, Director, re complaints; area political candidates, and related routine.
  - New York State District [folder 2 of 2], 1982 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - New York State District [folder 1 of 2], 1983 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    Re-structuring of 3 upstate councils; grievances and related routine.
  - New York State District [folder 2 of 2], 1983 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - New York State District [folder 1 of 2], 1984 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    Grievances; retiree club activities; voter registration; and related routine.
  - New York State District [folder 2 of 2], 1984 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - New York State District [folder 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    Complaints and related routine.
  - New York State District [folder 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - New York State District, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    re imports and Textile and Apparel Trade Enforcement Act; NLRB election for Professional and Commercial Employees Union-ILGWU (PACE); and related routine.
  - Pennsylvania. Central Pennsylvania District Council, 1961-1975 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    Financial data; complaints; trusteeship situation of Local 196 (Harrisburg); By-Laws; and related routine.
  - Pennsylvania. Western Pennsylvania District Council, 1958-1973 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    Application for charter as District Council; completed annual report forms; and related routine.
  - Philadelphia Area Council, 1973-1977 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    Review of operations of Philadelphia Health Center; imports; unemployment; non-union work; and related routine.
  - Western Massachusetts District Council, 1950-1956 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    With Chaikin, Manager (Springfield, Mass.) re lectures, speeches; testimonial dinner for Chaikin upon his promotion to Director of Texas area (1955); and letters of congratulations; includes news clippings of Chaikin activities during this time period.
- Series VI. Local Files, 1969-1986
  Arranged in numerical order by local number.
  - Local 1; 1-35, 1977-1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Correspondence re claim for liquidated damages for Herman Kay Co., Inc.; and related routine.
  - Local 10 [folder 1 of 2], 1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    re case of Tomas Rosario vs. Abe Dolgen, Manager, Local 10.
  - Local 10 [folder 2 of 2], 1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Local 10, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 4-11)
    re case of Abe Dolgen, Manager, Local 10 vs. Rosario, Vega and Cabel. obstruction and interference of usual business of Local 10. includes appeals, correspondence, handwritten notes, exhibits, GEB Appeals Committee documents, legal documents, and minutes.
  - Local 10, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    "The Union and Cutting Contractors," submitted to General Executive Board Committee, Local 10, Feb. 10, 1976 by Jay Mazur. 16 p. + exhibits.
  - Local 10 [folder 1 of 4], 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    re case of David Spitzer and Raymond Cabel vs. Nat Klein and Enzo Baldino (supplying copies of Executive Board minutes and recording of meetings). includes correspondence, minutes, reports, and related documents.
  - Local 10 [folder 2 of 4], 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Local 10 [folder 3 of 4], 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Local 10 [folder 4 of 4], 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Local 10, 1972-1986 (Box 11, Folder 17-35)
    re complaints, negotiations, benefits for retirees and active employees, and other related routine local matters.
  - Local 20, 1973-1976 (Box 11, Folder 35a)
    Related routine local matters.
  - Local 22, 1975-1984 (Box 11, Folder 36-40)
    re benefits; complaints and related routine.
  - Local 23-25, 1975-1986 (Box 11, Folder 41-48)
    Regarding Yves St. Laurent Sportswear Inc. operation in the U.S.; legal documents re Jou-Jou Designs vs. ILGWU; cuts in benefit funds; draft copy of agreement between Local 23-25 and Local 10 with Greater Blouse, Skirt, and Undergarment Association Inc. (1985-87); establishment of a Sportswear Industry Holiday Pay Commission; contract proposals; use of non-ILG contractors by Suitime; complaints; Greater Blouse, Skirt, and Undergarment Association accused of being dominated by organized crime by "Leichter Report"; Chinatown garment industry and other matters.
  - Local 23-25, 1975-1982 (Box 12, Folder 1-13)